# **Ovarro Hanson**

Dudley, West Midlands
Phone: 07498167172 - ovarrohanson18@yahoo.com,

linkedin.com/in/ovarro-hanson, https://github.com/Ohanson18

## **Professional summary**

Dedicated and versatile professional with over seven years of expertise in combined management and customer service, along with a passion for AWS services. Recently I completed 12 weeks of intense remote training with Generation, on the AWS re/Start programme. During this time, I gained substantial knowledge of IT fundamental skills and relevant soft skills. Keen to put this training into action and further develop my capabilities, as I work towards my career goal of becoming a Cloud Solutions Architect.

#### Skill

- Linux
- Python
- Networking
- AWS-Cloud Computing concepts and core services
- Time management
- Customer service
- Critical thinking
- Administration and management
- Git/GitHub

## **Experience**

15/07/2020 09/2020

#### AWS re/Start program

#### **Cloud Operation engineer**

- Covered the following: Linux (CLI), Networking, Security, Programming and Databases, Python, Cloud Computing concepts and core services.
- Hands-on experience using AWS services such as: launching EC2 and adding security groups, using Auto Scaling, troubleshooting VPC.
- Writing both Python and Bash Scripts to execute a task.
- Using Git/GitHub and knowledge of CI/CD, such as agile and waterfall.
- Soft skills: proactiveness, future orientation, persistence and teamwork.

05/2013 to 11/2019

#### **Property Manager**

#### Bromfield's Property - Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

- Collect and deposit money into accounts, disburse funds from cash accounts to pay bills or invoices, keep records of collections and disbursements, and ensure that accounts are balanced.
- Function as liaisons between tenants and owners ensuring effective

communication.

- Investigate complaints, disturbances and violations and resolve problems following management rules and regulations.
- This role allowed me to build excellent communication and persuasive skills, along with improving my numerical reasoning.

03/2013 to 11/2019

#### **General Manager**

Young Dreamers Research Centre - Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

- Use computers for various applications, such as: creating excel documents, word processing, run different software's and configuring network.
- Cost optimisations for the business.
- Configure routers, smart devices such as: tablets and phone.
- Build relationships with third party and subcontractor.
- In this role I learned how to take personal responsibility, demonstrated teamwork and adopted growth mindset and persistence.

09/2018 to 10/2019

#### **Private Hire Taxi**

Self Employed - Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

- Follow safety regulations and laws governing vehicle operation and ensure that
  passengers follow safety regulations. Also arrange to pick up customers on a
  regular schedule.
- This job allowed me to better develop my customer service and time management skills.

#### Education

03/2020 Generation UK and Ireland

AWS re/Start program

07/2009 Human Employment and Resource Training Trust/National Training Agency

Electrical Installation: level 2 -the equivalent to a BTEC Diploma

#### **Interests**

- Volunteering and community Involvement: National Youth Council of Jamaica, PRO for the parish of St. Elizabeth (2018-2019)
- Carpentry
- Nature walks, spending time with family and friends
- Puzzles

### **Achievement**

09/2020 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner certification

03/2020 Highfield level 2 award in the principles of fire safety (RQF)